It doesn't matter, right? Golf,
you can have the middest rig in the world-
Yeah
... and be an absolute killer.
Mm.
There are so many cringe-worthy people
online that are like,
"Ryan here started off
having 2K months,
and now he's doing 10K every..." We're not
going to do that.
We're just going to play some golf.
I haven't played in 14 years.
I'm feeling like-
Can already see that it's shit.
It's already shit.
Do you know what?
I think I'm going to surprise a lot of
people today.
Whether good, whether bad, I'm not sure.
So people watching,
they're just going to learn a lot today.
I can feel it.
First of all, dress code.
Yeah. [laughs]
What are you telling me?
I can't wear a T-shirt?
No.
I do not-
No
... own anything with a collar.
Why do you have to wear a collar?
Is it like a traditional thing,
the collar?
It's just the dress code, mate.
It's just the dress code.
It's like a-
It makes no difference, but-
It's just to keep out the ruffians.
We've got to play by the rules
If we hit anyone with the golf ball
and they say,
"Man in the blue shirt," we'll
turn it inside out. Let's get out of here.
Do you know what? I'm feeling confident.
A couple of birdies, maybe an eagle.
Is it Tiger Woods Golf on the iPad?
Yep.
Pretty good.
Yeah.
How are you?
Everyone's good at that.
Same, same.
Same, same. We'll see.
Take a shoot into the west.
That northeast is going to come across.
This kind of humidity might cause a bit of
havoc on the in-swingers, but apart from
that, we'll be good. Day for it. Ah.
Just got to be careful I don't hit the
ball too far or too perfect.
Don't want to show up Ryan.
There's going to be some golf enthusiasts
literally
just so excited to see this.
Yeah.
This is like me watching people do jujitsu
for the first time.
It's okay. I think a toe ball into the
water could be first shot,
just by your move-
That means that way?
Yeah. Just by your movement.
I've got a,
I do swing them out to the right a little
bit.
Yeah.
Can we build on it?
We can build on it, yes.
So what would I need to do to stop it-
So Declan, if you come in here, right,
the first thing I see is this.
This is what we call a weak lead hand
grip.
So lead hand being obviously lead side.
So you've got your grip straight away.
You've got it way too under the grip.
So that will open the face.
See the club face there?
Okay.
So to stop it going that way,
we need to wrap that more on there.
Yeah. So if we go... Yeah, that was good.
Yeah. There you go. Perfect.
More. And then close up that thumb.
Perfect.
So that's now, see how
that face now wants to go that way?
Yeah.
So that'll stop that, theoretically.
Okay. All right.
So straightaway-
So then from here-
Just do what you're doing, yeah.
It's actually not bad.
It's actually not bad at all.
I'm really worried about this dog.
[laughs]
Okay. That makes a lot of sense, actually.
Yeah.
So to start with,
I'm sure bringing the thumb in a bit so
that as we connect, we're
actually going to have a little bit of an
angle.
Well, you don't want it to be closed,
but before, when you were gripping it this
way, there was a very high chance
that through impact, that face
is going to point
that way.
Okay.
So if you just leave everything the same
but wrap that hand over, that club face
will close up a little bit more.
I feel like I should be paying for this.
Right, here we go. One more.
Better.
I'm
really worried about the people in front
of us.
[laughs]
And if it's going from your shot four-
Yes
... God, I'm nervous.
But if you're going for these guys,
we're not going to have enough time.
So that's the danger.
Okay. So one more,
just swing here through,
and just try not to hit it too hard.
Let the club
do the work.
Done.
Do you know what?
I think my eyesight's going as well.
I think I was a bit younger last time I
was here.
[laughs]
I didn't even see where that went.
Use that.
Okay, cool.
Should I go for another practice swing
or just go in?
Just go.
Cool. So you see that?
Yep.
Is it worth looking before you swing
or just focus on the ball?
Look out into the target,
but in all fairness, it, I mean [laughs]
let's just see what happens here.
Okay.
I have no idea where that's gone.
It's nearly hit old mate.
But didn't I just tell you though,
before you even
hit a shot,
I knew it was going that way, right?
Just-
Did it go over that way?
Well, yeah. It just went,
it went straight over to where that guy
is over there.
Sign of a good coach-
[laughs]
...
knowing where the ball's going to go
before someone hits it.
So did I first meet you at the Business
Day 2021?
Yeah, so I reckon
that would've been the first interaction I
had with you
live. Yeah.
Yeah, and I brought Taylor on.
No, I was at the one before that.
So I've come to two.
So I came to your first one,
then the second one,
you brought Taylor along.
Okay.
Mm.
So when was the one before that?
Was it in Sydney?
Yes. Yeah.
With the roundhouse?
Yeah.
With the round tables?
Okay, cool.
Yeah.
Yeah, that makes sense.
Yeah, I remember that one. That
was like 400 people. Darren was at
that one.
Yes, he was.
Yeah.
And then the other one was-
Yeah
... just after lockdown.
Yeah.
That would've been 2019.
That's quite a long time.
Mm. But I just realized,
after coming to that one, I
was still doing a
lot of in-person coaching.
Mm.
And I realized that what you were saying,
I could incorporate into my in-person
stuff,
but I knew I couldn't go further than the
in-person stuff.
I was like,
"I've got to find a way to actually get
this all online so
I can actually scale it."
Yeah. How long have you been online now?
Three years. Yeah.
Do you think you'd go back?
I would never go back to in-person.
[laughs] No.
Do you know what, John?
It sounds bad from me off.
I say the same thing, but it's not.
I actually loved in person.
Yeah.
It's the energy.
And it sounds like such a woo term.
I just can't give someone an hour of
energy in person, because
that hour of energy on my laptop
or my phone could be so
much more productive.
Yeah.
I could service so many more people.
It's actually why I'm trying to do less
and less calls because,
and the Discord can
seem like a cop-out,
but I enjoy it because, one,
I can read what someone
said, I can take time to think about it,
then actually my ideas come as I'm typing
a response.
Yeah.
And then sometimes two days later I'll
have an idea and go back to that person's
slide.
Yeah.
Whereas on a call it's very condensed.
Like personal training-
Yeah
... you'd have to get everything into
that one hour,
then you wouldn't see them for
six days and-
Yeah
... 23 hours.
So I like more of like a pit patter,
messaging, breaking it
up, getting back to people. Also,
to go away and get them to do stuff.
And ideating 10 ideas for content might
take two days.
Mm.
Whereas in person,
it's essential at first because we've got
a lot of people in the
Discord-
Yeah
...
that don't think they need to do in person
before going online.
And they get roasted a little bit.
[laughs]
They do. You can tell
if I've had a coffee.
But you needed to respect how many,
you did thousands of golf sessions.
Yeah, I did. I did six years,
10 to 12 hours a day,
before I even thought about online.
So yeah,
you've got to do your hard yards first
and, again, you get to
coach all different types of people,
and then you can actually-
Because exactly like what you said here,
you need to be able to look at someone in
a snapshot and know the issue.
Yeah.
Same as if you're Ed Lawrence,
you look at someone's YouTube,
you know the problem.
You look at someone's backswing,
And if you just don't have
that experience,
and it's so clear to see who hasn't
done in person, because when they try
and explain what they do, it's waffle.
Mm.
And it sounds so bad to say that,
but it's just waffle.
There's no specifics.
You can't see who the avatar is.
You can't see who the person is.
They're just making like a word jumble,
and you're like, "Bro, you've never worked
with people in person."
Yeah.
Because I bet when you got into golf,
you're like, "Oh, I might help some pros,
might work with this."
And then you realize you're working with
semi-retired
42-year-olds that have just been divorced
and want to hang out with the boys more.
Yeah, correct.
Okay So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to wrap my hand in a little
bit more.
Yep.
So you happy with that degree?
More.
Oh, really?
Yeah. There you go. Perfect.
And then do I want to line my thumbs up
or come over the top?
Go a little bit more under with
that bottom hand. Yep,
a little bit too much.
There you go. So more from the side.
Perfect.
And then from here?
Yep.
Do I need to get a little bit lower?
No, you're all right.
Run through. There you go. It's through.
Do you know what?
There's a few things we could say here.
It went straight.
It did.
So we'll take that.
Yeah.
We're working, we're building.
[laughs] All right.
We're moving in the right direction.
We shall try and get up there as far as we
can.
Would you say I just got too much on top
of it?
Well, yeah,
you hit the top of the ball there.
Okay. Do you know what?
I care about the land,
I care about the soil.
What I didn't want to do
is leave a trail of divots.
So we're calibrating,
we're course-correcting.
We're getting it. Well,
we're not going to need to go
and fetch that ball.
It's right in our line.
Sometimes you've got to walk before you
run, Declan.
That's right.
Part of me would love to get LASIK eye
surgery, but this is the problem, though.
There are some people.
Have you heard about the people
that kill themselves?
You heard about this?
No.
So LASIK surgery,
the majority of the time, I'm sure,
goes right, but in some
cases, it fucks people up.
But I think just the odds, right?
So you know Whistling Diesel,
the YouTuber?
He had it, and he said it
was the worst decision of his life.
He can't open his eyes without eye drops,
has to wear sunglasses outside for the
rest of his life,
super sensitive to light.
But there's women who the pain
and the stinging and everything,
it's detached them
from their family.
They end up topping themselves.
Yeah, right.
So I'm like,
is it worth it for a golf ball?
Because I know my luck, right?
My life's great. Everything about it
is great.
I'm kind of waiting for
that one thing to come along
that ruins it.
[laughs]
And it would just so happen to be
something like James wanted better eyes,
so he did this,
and now next minute he's dead.
Do you know what?
When you look at the LASIK conventions,
all the doctors are wearing glasses.
Mm.
Every practice swing,
you should be trying to at least brush
that ground.
Now, I want you to do one more thing, too.
Take a practice swing.
Oh, he did it okay that time.
I want you to keep that left foot
down.
Okay.
So when you take a practice swing,
you keep lifting
that left foot up a little bit
too much.
Ah.
Yeah, correct.
Like hello sailor.
Well, yeah. So the reason why you do that,
though, is because, take your setup
again.
When you actually swing the club back,
you're moving too much off the ball
this way.
Okay.
Right?
So if we want to hit ahead of the golf
ball, makes sense to stay a
little bit more centered-
Okay
... when you make a backswing.
Cool. A bit like boxing,
you don't want to actually-
Yeah, correct
... take your... Okay.
Yeah.
And for this,
we're not going to have to worry about the
face opening too much, or
we're going to do the same again?
No. Well,
you want it as square as you can, ideally.
So let's go one, two.
Yep. So yep, perfect.
Ball position a little bit more back.
So you go towards the target more.
Keep going. Good, there you go.
Perfect.
Okay.
And I'm just going to help your grip out a
little bit.
We're going to get into the nitty-gritty
here.
Okay, take that off, wrap that around.
Perfect. Thumb right there. Perfect.
There's your grip, right? Does
that feel weird?
No, that's okay.
Okay, cool. This one's going to come in.
Good, grip it around. So that's okay.
Now, you've got a 10-finger grip.
I might change that a little bit later on.
Wrap this over. Good. That's perfect.
Okay. Square that face up.
Stay centered. So just make a backswing.
Don't hit the ball, just make a backswing.
Good.
So try and stay a little bit more over
this way.
I think I'm just a bit stiff-
There you go
... in the shoulder.
You are stiff, yes.
It's the lower back and all that.
PT.
Yeah, that's it. Okay.
Declan, you're worrying me there.
Can you move out the-
No, you're good
... way a tiny bit? It's just that.
Ah. How good's that? There you go.
Look at that, fast learner. Fast learner.
It's good techies, that.
Yeah.
That's going to look good on Twitter.
There you go. [laughs]
They're not going to know who the fuck I
am on Twitter, though.
[laughs]
Well, there's the anti-vaxxer.
Or they might do. No, I'm joking.
[laughs] Well, that one felt good.
There you go.
Do you know what?
Now the nerves have been settled a bit,
I'm ready for the next
hole.
[laughs]
That first one, I was nervous.
Did you actually feel a little bit
nervous?
Yeah,
because I was really worried about hitting
that dog.
Yeah. [laughs]
Imagine.
Pew. Dong.
Yeah.
And then the poor bit, the dog's like,
"Ah."
Yeah.
And then the groundsman comes over
and he's like,
"You killed my dog."
[laughs]
That, I just couldn't live with. Again,
you know, like the LASIK thing.
Yeah.
People go, "Oh,
how's your day going?" "Yeah,
I killed someone's dog today."
[laughs]
"How?" "Tried golf." "Didn't know you
played golf." "Haven't played in 15
years."
So yeah.
I would say you don't go this way coming
from, but you do.
I'm assuming
we go that way.
See,
that's actually quite a nice little beach,
that.
I've never even seen this before.
Look at that.
It's why you come to Australia.
Your most average beach here
is better than our best beach in the UK.
You been to the UK?
No.
Do you know what? Aussies.
Have you been to Europe?
No. US, but not Europe yet.
So many Aussies haven't been to Europe
and haven't been to the UK.
Do you know what? I don't blame them.
It's not all that.
Now, the UK is great, Europe is great,
but I can understand.
We go to Europe so much because we've got
nothing in the UK, but if this is your
backyard-
Mm
... someone's like, "Oh,
do you want to sit on a plane for 20 hours
to do the same
thing?" Probably not.
Ready to go again?
Yep.
Right.
Should we just smash it into the apartment
block-
Yeah
... and see what happens?
That's where my inner demon just goes,
"Let's hit one at
the apartments."
So it looks like pretty straightforward
hole.
Obviously,
don't want to go too far to the right,
so I'll just hug the left-hand
side pretty-
Yeah, we could be on the beach knowing me.
Oh, that's real nice.
Ah, it's pure. Not too bad.
Oh,
just off to the right into the sand a bit.
Little bit.
That's all right.
Compared to the last one.
Yeah.
So we're starting to see a little bit of a
common theme.
You need to start, well,
we either fix it on course, which
is sometimes really hard
to do,
or we just aim more left to allow for it
to go a little bit
right.
Okay.
Because otherwise,
if we're always aiming at the middle of
the fairway and you're
always hitting it to the right,
it's just always going to happen.
Yeah, cool.
So while you're on the course,
until you're learning it,
just aim a little right.
Start aiming at 11.
Yeah. Yep.
Cool. That felt better, that.
Yeah.
My lower back's getting a bit of-
[laughs]
... jib. That's all right.
Your biggest struggle at the moment
is scaling.
Yeah. So essentially, yes.
I've got a lot of online students.
You can only take on a certain amount
before your days just start to
get to a point where that's all you're
doing, and then the other parts of your
business kind of stay stagnant because
you've got no time for content, or you're
working till 10:00, like I do.
[laughs]
10:00 at night trying to get everything
done.
But then also it's like the content I am
creating brings in more business, which
then makes me more busy.
Yeah.
And then it's just a complete go-around.
I can relate to that.
And then sometimes you have hesitancy
because if you put your
prices up to reduce the flow of business
coming in, you could end up in a position
where you've then got less business,
which requires more marketing-
Yeah
... even for more money.
So then there's more effort, more money,
but you're still
in the same 10:00 PM cycle.
But that's why I created the academy,
which is a lower-priced
option. Obviously,
it's a little bit less one-to-one
instruction.
Mm.
But if someone wants to join that,
that's the
opportunity to do it there.
So I'm currently building that out to
actually try and make it more one-to-one,
but to be able to service a lot more
people,
but not for it to take up too much of my
time.
Yeah.
Because obviously the one-to-one stuff's
where I place all my energy.
It's interesting because that's what I'm
doing at the moment, and instead of
being a digital course, I try
and make it an asset
that reduces the amount of
questions that people have.
Yep.
So for instance, if you
were to build out all of the
infrastructure that says, "If
you hit left, watch this.
If you hit right, watch this.
If you don't hit far enough, watch this.
If your left heel comes up,
watch this." Almost, I'm sure with the way
that AI's going,
there's soon going to be a bot where
someone records their swing,
and AI then tells them what videos to
watch in what order.
Yeah.
Then you create a community environment
that does two things.
It gives people access to you where they
can ask you questions, but you can very
soon spot... Is that mine?
Yes.
Good. That's not bad at all. So then
that means that, in essence,
if you spot a pattern of people asking you
stuff, it shows you a white space in
your education system.
Yeah.
And then you can just keep plotting holes,
so eventually the conversations die-
Yeah
... down a little bit,
and you can point people to resources.
Yeah.
Then if you are asking
or answering people's questions, you go,
"Fair enough, I
obviously didn't give enough detail into
that area."
Yeah.
This whole low-ticket thing
is where so many businesses get
excited. They go, "Oh,
I could just charge a quarter
and just get 1,000 people on
that."
Yeah.
But they don't appreciate the difficulty.
Sometimes it's five times the work to
charge people a fifth of the price-
Mm
... and have five times more people.
Yeah. But we-
Is that normal?
We won't tell anyone.
No, that's okay.
Yours is over there. It's gone.
No.
Yeah.
Nah, surely.
Do you have to be careful for snakes in
Sydney in there?
I was just about to say that.
Because in Brissy or the Gold Coast,
there's no chance.
Like-
Yeah, you're not going in my brother
... it's just, "No,
I'm not going to do it."
Well, so we're talking about snakes.
We talking about Lucas or-
Oh
... sorry. [laughs]
[laughs] You edit that out or?
No, I keep it in. [laughs]
Perfect.
Cool. So we're going to sand a little bit.
There we go. Perfect.
And that's what we have the sand for.
Oh, nice. So again, see that right ball?
Yeah. I didn't aim left enough, did I?
No.
But at least I know where it went.
I can tell you've done this before.
I'm very good. No, I'm kidding.
I see you've played nice-
It's-
... too many before
... it's gone left. Yeah. But James,
to your point with the golf stuff,
take you for example,
you need someone telling
you what you actually are doing wrong.
You're never going to guess online what
you're doing.
That's the fricking problem with golf,
is you always need a pro to tell you,
"Hey,
you need to focus on these things."
Then-
Then you need to know how to practice
them.
There's big-
Then you got to put in the time
...
there's big opportunity as well because in
golf, when you do something wrong,
you get real-time feedback.
In weight training, you don't.
Yeah.
So when people are doing real suboptimal
shit in the gym, they think they're fine.
Yeah.
So at least you know
that every time someone misses the green,
they're building
some kind of psychological pain that's
going to build them up to the point that
they burst and hire someone.
Yeah.
Same in tennis.
Every time you shank a shot
or hit the net, you're like, "Fuck."
Yeah.
But in gym and training,
it's so easy to point to external
pressures.
Mm.
"Oh, it's my genetics,"
which in some cases it is.
"Oh, I'm just a hard gainer.
Oh." So it's like almost that
bucket has got a bigger hole in the
fitness industry.
You've got to put so many in.
Yeah.
So at least so many of your leads kind of
qualify themselves and come to you and
they're like, "Mate, I need help."
Yeah.
Whereas in fitness, people are reluctant,
especially men, right?
Yeah.
Majority of my clients over the years have
been women.
Yeah.
In business, they're men.
Smaller feet. Go feet smaller,
so closer together. Good.
Small swing.
That far?
Yep, that's fine.
Right. [laughs]
It's a hard game, isn't it?
Do you know what? Think about it less.
Just be at one with the ball.
It's going to be a long day.
[laughs]
With your Discord-
Yeah
...
because that's why I messaged you the
other... Wait.
Yeah.
Are you going to get to a point where you
just can't stand going in there anymore?
No. To be fair, it sounds
pretty bad,
but if I ever feel like I'm doing too much
work, I have a look at my
stripe and then like- [laughs]
That sounds like such a dickheadish thing
to say
because for me, it's not the work,
it's the money you get for the work.
Yep.
So there are so many people
that become disenfranchised with doing the
work, and
they put their prices up,
and then they're fine about it.
Yeah.
We got the lady with the horse
nutritionist business, Claire.
Oh, that yeah.
And she's like, "I hate one-to-ones."
And I'm like, "Well, if you doubled your
price, you might not."
Yeah.
So a lot of the time I feel
that it can be for people
that they're just not getting
paid well enough.
Yeah.
For me,
I still enjoy the Discord because it
is a finger on the pulse of people's
problems, and I can say firsthand
that when I left
the fitness
industry to run a fitness business,
I lost that finger on the pulse.
Yep.
So I remember knowing what it felt like to
lose touch with the fitness industry,
and then business started to reflect that.
However, I think that
was just an interest change.
I think when I started doing jujitsu,
I stopped caring about fitness.
Mm-hmm.
Because if someone said, "Oh, mate,
there's all this new evidence coming out
about
length and muscle stretch
and hypertrophy," I was like,
"I don't care."
Mm.
"I want to know how to choke people out."
So jujitsu pretty much cannibalized
my fitness career because I
was spending two hours a day training
jujitsu.
If I'd spent those two hours a day in the
evidence-based science field, whatever.
So no, I like the Discord.
It can get a bit hectic at times.
Today, I emptied it before I came.
Yeah.
The hard part's when you have a kid.
Right.
Because I'm most productive in the
morning.
Yeah.
So sometimes at 8:30,
your missus needs to have a shower,
needs to do
something,
and you get the baby for half an hour.
Yeah.
And you struggle because you really want
to spend time with your child, but at the
same time,
your most productive time's slipping away
from you.
And when you know
that work's just building and building,
then you're just like, "I
need to empty it."
And sometimes I think about not working
weekends, but then that makes Mondays
worse.
Yeah.
So, yeah.
It's one of those. But even, there
are some times I really enjoy doing the
Discord,
like on a plane, and just-
Yep
... chatting to people,
helping them out with stuff.
I know it kind of makes it a bit of a
differentiator.
I know some people get really overwhelmed
with having different threads to talk-
Yeah
... people in. But for me, I like it.
And also, it means little things.
Say we run a Nutonic discount,
or we do an event,
or we're doing anything, to be
able to go to the Discord
and have loads of super warm people
that want to be
receptive to your stuff-
Yeah
... I think that's quite valuable.
But yeah, it's quite cool.
There are people making friends in there.
But no, it's cool.
And then when we do the events,
you can see all the people hanging out
together.
Catherine Sargent, Craig Jackson, Jayden,
Chelsea.
I knew quite a lot of the people in the
JSA, but with the business thing,
because I'm reviewing people's content-
Mm
... so much,
I feel like I have a better connection
with them because when you
scale a fitness business,
you have to give the workouts away.
Yeah.
And then you're actually giving away most
of the communications you have with
people.
Yeah.
And also,
I think business owners just respect your
time a bit more.
Yeah. 100%, they do, yeah. I
felt like I burnt out in person
when the amount of work
I was doing wasn't reflected in my bank
account.
Yeah.
I was just like, "Dude,
I'm working so much," and I'm just like,
"Is that
what I bought in?" I'm like,
"That's way too much effort for what I'm
bringing in."
Whereas online,
it's the complete opposite, right?
I'm just like, "Whoa,
I want to do more of that."
Mm.
So yeah,
I can understand where the Discord
sometimes might feel like, "Oh, man,
I've got to clear it,"
but then at the same time, like you said,
right-
Do you know what?
And also now I've just realized,
and we can even put this in the
edit,
I'm going to have the Discord full of
people that I can give value to, but
also respect my time, and
if anyone doesn't do that,
I'll just refund them.
Yeah.
And if I see someone that's coming in
that looks like a lot of hard work, a bit
like if you're in a relationship with a
chick who's too high maintenance, you're
like, "This just isn't worth it."
Yeah.
You just back out. So yeah.
And then there's no hard feelings.
I'm like, "Hey mate,
seems like you need a little bit more than
what I'm offering.
Here's your money back." Have you found a
good editor yet?
Yes.
Do they live local or are they online?
No. UK.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
Do they play golf?
No. So you'd actually know him. Oliver Ty.
Oliver Ty.
He did your edit ages ago, and he
was one of my favorite social
media brands, James Smith,
and he did an edit for you on Twitter.
And I saw it, and I was like, "Dude,
this is sick." So I reached out to him
and I'm
like, "Can you help me out?"
Do you know what kills me, right? And
if you're an editor watching this, people
that spend too long on the edit.
Yep.
So it sounds mad.
We will film at 11:00 AM a jujitsu class.
We'll put the video out at 8:00 PM.
Yep.
Sometimes people are like, "Oh, James,
I want to be your editor." I'm like,
"Sweet." Then four or five days, I'm like,
I haven't heard anything.
I'm like, if you want to win my business,
just work late tonight.
Yeah. [laughs]
And also I would rather have a faster
edit, minimalist edited-
Yep
... than you way over-edit it
and spend too long.
Yeah.
Because I feel like as a creator,
there's a real short period of time where
basically, when I get an idea,
I want to film, and when I want to film,
I want it
edited so I can post it,
so I can get the dopamine,
and I can go back into the
cycle. And I said that to Declan early on.
He was at uni.
I was like, "I'll pay you more,
I just want it done sooner."
Yeah.
And yeah. Some people out there,
one of his mates was doing some free
videography for someone else that we know.
It's two weeks later
and I hadn't got an edit.
It's like, mate,
who's going to hire you if you're slow?
Get someone the first re-
Mm.
He's good. Gets me the first review,
send it back, bit more B-roll.
But he does send me edits at 2:00 AM
sometimes.
I'm like, "You don't have to stay up
that late, but I appreciate it." Are you
itching to have a shot, Declan?
We'll get one.
Well,
do you want to have a driver back from
here?
Yeah.
You're not allowed to have a warm-up shot.
You never play golf.
Yeah. So let's see the
practice swing first. So similar to James,
I'll be able to tell, right?
So
[laughs]
I doubt he's going to make contact.
Let me just see. I just want to see.
I don't think- Yeah,
I want to see you hit a ball.
We'll give you another shot.
Oh, he did. Right.
It's always right. Yeah.
It's always right. All right.
Let me see if I can fix this. This
is a tough one, but I won't give you an
$8 golf ball.
I'll give you a $4 golf ball. Thank you.
Thank you. Yes. Okay.
Pop it back on the tee.
Let's work some magic here. Okay.
Set up to the ball for me. All right.
So we're going to go,
so right now you're standing way too
upright. Okay. Okay.
So stand further away.
Good. Hands closer together.
See how he's got the same grip as you?
Everyone does it, right?
All right. So we're going to go in,
take this one off. Okay.
Thumb closer to there.
Wrap it on top. Does that feel weird?
Yeah. Yep.
That hand, good. That's pretty good. Okay.
Fine.
Stance, pretty good.
You know what? I quite like that.
Let's rip it. So like this?
Yep, just- And just- Yep. Off you go.
Oh. Oh. [laughs] Smoked it.
Well done. All good. [laughs]
[laughs] Do you know what?
The majority of everything I do
is just saying to
people, "If it's good, do it again.
If it's not good, make it better."
Yeah.
Same as golf, right?
You hit a good shot. Cool.
Keep doing that.
Yeah.
You have a bad shot,
that needs to get better.
Yeah.
So many people will just like,
they'll create a narrative.
"Oh,
I'm just not good at golf." You're like,
mate, behind every good golfer was
someone that couldn't hit a ball.
Right.
Declan's qualified PT as well.
Oh, is he?
Yeah. Got him out. Saved you. Saved you,
Declan.
[laughs]
No worries.
You were doing them in the city as well,
weren't you?
Yeah.
Living out west, in the city. I was like,
"Mate, come let me give you an easier
life." What's good about Declan is
if we don't have much work, he pesters me.
He's like, "Make some videos.
Give me something to edit." It's actually
quite nice
just being out in nature.
Bit of wet grass. Not too hot.
Just invested in a TRT company called
Manual in the UK.
And so those things
are going to come out soon.
Then bringing the podcast back
and whatever.
So within the next 12 months,
I will have then suddenly a
portfolio will start to appear of
companies that I've invested in
or raised money
from. So there's loads of people
that will be like, "Oh,
you're just a course bro."
And then my manager will be in the
comments like, "Where's your $20 million
business?" Or whatever.
Yeah.
And then all the things that we've said,
the way we've launched Nutonic, not much
paid, mostly organic,
personal brand first, email marketing,
all of those things.
So then people will go, "All right,
so I viewed the PT." And we'll be like,
"Oh,
actually, we pivoted
and made a beverage business."
Yeah.
So you just add more stock to your
position.
It's pretty crazy though,
where you've come from.
Like-
PTing
... PTing on the floor.
Yeah.
Like-
Yeah, but do you know what I think?
Same as golf, right?
When you're younger, you kind of go,
"This is it now."
Yeah.
And you settle in going,
"I'm just going to help people for six
hours a day for the
rest of my life."
Yeah.
So then every other opportunity
that presents itself, you're like, "Oh,
this is
easy."
Mm.
"Oh,
I've just got to be on my phone for six
hours today." Oh, that's all right.
Even today you've gone,
"I'm going to fly from Queensland to New
South
Wales for a content opportunity
that might not even be fruition."
Yep.
Oh, that's easy.
Yeah.
Management expense, the whole thing.
So if you come from a really difficult
business, everything else is kind
of easy in comparison.
Yeah.
That's why I think coaches often make good
entrepreneurs, or the other one would
be nightclub promoters.
Like Chris Williamson, my manager,
they used to
be nightclub promoters.
Once you can get people into an
establishment to get pissed
and operate a business till 3:00 in the
morning, suddenly
everything else seems pretty easy in
comparison.
Yeah.
My manager runs an event. He's like,
"What?
People aren't going to be drunk
and trying to finger each other in the
toilets and
try and stab a bouncer. That's easy."
Yeah.
It's just crazy the way the world works
now.
Would you say that in-person PTing would
ever go away?
Do you know what?
I'm excited for GLP-1s to change the
world.
So Ozempic, Wegovy, Mounjaro, Tirzepatide,
they're only
going to get better,
and I'm really excited for cohorts of
millions of people to go to the gym
that have never been in the gym before.
Yep.
We always forget
that only 15% of the world have a gym
membership.
Right.
Well, actually, no. 15% of the UK.
The world would be way less.
So we're going to have all of these people
coming into a gym that don't know what
the lever on a leg press does.
They don't know what the hands onto the
seat of a
leg extension does.
So AI won't replace those people.
So as long as people can create a business
flow funnel that those people that have
lost the weight that want to preserve
muscle and everything else can find their
way
into the gym,
there's going to be a whole fitness
revolution with that.
Yeah
So it's so much easier to fall off
when you're fat than it
is to fall off when
you're lean.
Mm.
Plus,
your body's just way more forgiving for
excess calories when you're leaner.
You're more insulin sensitive,
you're more inclined to train,
you're more inclined
to go exercise after you eat like shit.
So we're going to flip the whole
motivational scale around,
where we're going to
say to people, "Hey, you're 120 kg,
take this. Cool.
You're now 90,
now work as hard as you can." Because
if you never take the drug
again, cool, but even
if you do take the drug again,
your personal best should be
how long can you go without taking the
drug again?
Yeah.
6 months, 12 months, 18 months.
And then guess what, guys?
No matter what happens in your life,
you're just one doctor consult away from
making it go away.
Yeah.
Which is crazy.
Mm.
If you said to me,
"I need you lean for January." I'd go,
"Fuck,
Christmas, got Christmas parties,
got this." If you take a GLP-1,
the idea of
bruising just makes you feel-
Mm.
Yeah, they're crazy.
I used to make content hating them,
which we have in the
Discord, a lot of people-
Yeah
... going against them. I'm like, "Guys,
you've never tried one."
Yeah.
And when people try them,
some are glue-sided,
Ozempic makes me feel a bit nauseous,
but Mounjaro, there's
none.
Right.
500 bucks a month,
everything taken care of.
Yeah.
And I'd be interested to see a cohort of
people that are weight training
properly, eating well. Mate,
it's post-nut clarity for your appetite.
It's like you've just had a wank.
You know if someone says, "Oh,
do you want to go to a strip club?" after
you've had
a wank, you'd be like,
"No." That's what it's like around food.
"Do you want to get McDonald's?" You're
like, "Let's have sushi." You got any fat
friends or relatives?
Um.
Who's your fattest mate?
What's their name?
What's their?
Who's your fattest mate?
You know what?
I actually don't have a lot of fat mates.
Fatphobic bastard. Look at that.
I actually don't.
I can name loads.
[club hits ball]
There you go. That was pure. Straight,
too.
Don't tell, show.
[chuckles]
Don't tell, show. Oh,
here's one interesting for you.
So you know we're doing the web critiques
at the moment.
Yep.
So basically, we have the 30 Days to
Improve Your Business.
Link will be in the description.
So then we started doing the online web
critiques, getting people to send
in their data for the critique.
But we then throw them into the 30-day
automation.
They're generating twice the revenue than
the organic
30-day automation.
Right.
So people that come for the web critique
and get bundled into an automation they
didn't even ask for-
Yep
...
are attributing double the revenue of just
the people that we get into the 30
day.
Because they're
super invested, right?
If they're willing to go, "You know what?
James helped me out," they're more likely
to join.
And then we just created the landing page
lead magnet.
So I started using rev track,
and with that, I looked at my videos
that get the
most clicks through from the description
or have landing page in the title.
So people that are coming to content
wanting to optimize landing pages are more
inclined to click for more information.
So we made that,
but we're currently in the process of
checking out what that
attribution looks like.
We need to grow it a little bit more
and get more data,
because with the 30-day lead magnet,
it takes us three weeks to see whether
or not
they're going to buy.
Yeah.
And we only made the lead magnet a few
weeks ago.
Oh, yeah, so from the event that we did,
so we had 600 people in London,
although the event did generate really
good amounts of money, the ads from that
event-
Yeah
... are killing it.
Yeah.
Once I saw the ads,
I would've done the event for free.
Yep.
So it's crazy.
Yep. That's good.
Very interesting. It's how the sausage
is made.
When you've got a missus and a child,
if you're like, "Oh, babe,
I've just been at
the gym," she's like, "Cool." If I'm like,
"Babe, I've just been at work," she's
like, "Cool." But if I say, "Babe,
I've just been having a sauna for an
hour,"
she's like, "What the fuck?
You're having a sauna.
I'm with the child here cleaning up poo."
Today, what do I say to her?
"Babe, been working." She's going to go,
"You've been playing golf, you prick.
You've been out there."
And the worst thing
is Tay doesn't complain about anything.
She'd never even call me a prick.
The fact of the matter is, there's just no
justifying this as work today.
I'm going to come home,
I'm going to be like, "Oh,
what a long day. I'm knackered. Oh,
put my feet up." She's going to be like,
"You've been playing golf with your mates,
pissing about making content." It's like
when I've got to go, "Oh babe,
I've got a work trip where?" I suppose all
mine go
to the right, so I shouldn't really be-
Yeah
... that worried.
[club hits ball] Wrong there.
It must've been the angle of the club, eh?
Well, again, where did you hit it?
Let's go again.
It's a $10 ball, so if you lose it...
[sighs] All right. Okay. Exactly.
And this time again.
So grip over. Good.
I think it was those people.
It's making me nervous.
Just try to see where the fucking flag...
Okay, I see it now.
You don't need to worry about the flag.
[club hits ball] Oh, how good's that?
Oh, God.
Oh, you freaking flew the tractors,
though. That's good. That's out there.
Nice.
At least it was in a semi straight line.
Yeah, it was good.
Draw as fuck, though. I
was literally aiming so far to the left.
Oh, God. Oh, a $10 ball flew better.
[chuckles] If someone
was new getting into content creation,
wanting to take their
business online,
what advice would you give them?
Man,
I would just say post something every day.
It doesn't have to be good,
but you've just got to get used to posting
every
single day. You know what I mean?
So many people would do anything apart
from that.
Oh, mate, it's-
"I'm thinking of,
should I be posting quality
or quantity?" You're like, "One a
day, mate."
Just post. Yeah, just post.
Oh, in my demographic,
I think maybe I could do three posts a
week.
I'm like, "Or just do one a day."
Yeah.
It's more like just the habits of doing
it.
If you were to go to the driving range
every day versus three days a week,
and you
were to hit half as many balls twice as
often, you'd still be hitting the same
amount of balls,
but you would get better phenomenally
faster just
having it as part of your identity
that you're someone
that hits balls every day.
Yeah. Correct.
But I think,
and you would be the same here, I've
posted videos in the past where I
was like, "I
don't even want to post this."
I don't even think it's a good reel.
I actually got a student from it.
Yeah. [chuckles]
You know what I mean?
Oh, I've had that.
I got a million followers from one
that I didn't even like it.
That was your TikTok one, right?
Swimmers Body Illusion, yeah. I was like,
"Oh, it's not really got anything to do
with fitness." A million followers later.
What must be unbearable for a lot of golf
instructors is to be so competent,
capable, and knowledgeable about golf-
Yeah
... and not to have a business
that reflects it.
Yep.
Because you actually don't need to be
that knowledgeable to be a good personal
trainer.
Yep.
You actually just need to be good
and kind with people
and give them what they
want.
Yep.
Whereas kindness won't go far
if you're getting spanked by your mates at
golf every
week.
Yeah.
So being a good PT
is probably 60% empathy-
Yep
... 40% skill.
Whereas being a good golf instructor,
some people don't care if
their golf instructor's a prick
if they're making them way better at golf.
Yeah, I think there's two sides to that.
You've got to know what you're doing.
You've got to know what to spot so
that you can actually fix someone pretty
quickly.
Just this morning I had a new student sign
up
because he took four in-person lessons
and he was like, "Dude, your
online lesson was literally hands down
better than all four of those combined."
Mm.
He's like,
"I've just signed up to your monthlies."
And I'm like, "Yeah, sweet." So
obviously my skills as a coach to spot
different things in the golf swing,
which is
a pretty complex thing,
obviously if that's good,
then they get better,
then they believe that I can
help them even more. I mean, like-
[horn honks] Oh, God, we're going to die
So this is what lady golfers do, right?
They didn't even hit a ball then.
They just yell it because they don't like
people being in front of them.
You're joking.
No, I'm not kidding. That's what they do.
So they're just saying
that because they're about to take a shot.
Yeah. Well, they want us out of the way.
Will we let them go past?
We will, yeah. But they-
Why'd you say lady golf?
Is it just a thing?
Uh-
We'll let people in the comments decide.
Yeah.
I've worked at a golf club for six years.
I know how it all operates.
But, yeah,
the B2B stuff, like I said, I
was an in-person coach for six
years, and man,
I just ground my backside off for six
years.
And, in three years online,
I'm doing far better
than I ever did in person.
Because you can't grind
that much in person.
To a certain extent, like-
Well, especially on the Gold Coast, right?
It's baking hot, middle of summer.
Whenever you get home after a long day,
the last thing you want to do is go back
out the next day and do it all over again.
Yeah.
At least with PT,
you're kind of half in the air con.
But outside and in the heat, it's brutal.
True. No summer, winter,
it's all the same in the gym.
It's all the same temperature.
Yeah. Correct.
Yeah. That's fair enough.
I think so many people just glaze over the
fact
that some people have to spend so long
getting good at stuff.
Yeah.
What geography are your clients?
US, UK.
See, the US market,
Americans have just got money.
Yeah. Well, for golf especially, yeah,
they're the biggest golf country in the
world. So-
And in business terms, Americans are like-
Yeah
... "Hey bro, just bought your course,
$3,000.
That's kind of a good deal." Okay.
Facing in a bit.
Yep.
Again, just move forwards. Good. Perfect.
[golf club hits] Oh, solid.
That's actually pretty good. There you go.
You'll be able to putt that.
First time playing in 12 years.
He said 14 at the start, though. So it's-
Yeah. 12, 14, it's one of those.
It's been a long time.
And the first three tee offs I went onto
the wrong course, so
just keep it on the same one.
Do you mind if we go through? Of course.
Yeah.
No problem. Calories in, calories out.
Oh, yeah. That's it, man.
[laughs] Golf's not my forte.
South African, isn't he?
Mm.
Do you know there's a saying in South
Africa, right?
Every time I meet a South African,
I unleash it then.
It's a really offensive thing you can say.
It's called, "Your mama's puss."
And every time you say it, people
are like,
"Oh, yeah. Hey, bro, that's not funny.
It's not funny, bro."
That I've never seen a South African just
laugh.
I think it means,
"Your mom's vagina." Every time there's
good banter, a
good crowd, everyone's getting on,
if you want a South African to...
that's what you say,
"Your mama's puss." My mate told me about
it once.
He said it and pissed off a
South African guy. So then ever since,
every time I've had a couple of beers,
every
time I meet a South African,
if I'd had one beer,
I would've just said it.
I would've put my arm around him
and just been, "Oh, your mama's puss."
[laughs]
And he would've been like,
"What'd you fucking say,
bro?" Ain't it mad, right?
Golf,
you can have the middest rig in the world-
Yeah
... and be an absolute killer.
Mm. Yep. Well, a lot of golf is-
Sloppy.
Yeah, sloppy.
Okay,
so we've spoken about posting frequency-
Yep
... emails. You host your landing page.
You don't use Leadpages, do you?
You use your website.
Yeah,
so I've got a lady who does all my website
stuff, which is
fantastic. She's really, really good.
I can't believe how many people
are against using
something like Leadpages. They're like,
"Oh, it's $49 a month." I'm like, "Guys,
business expense, write it off,
make it look good." But that's where they
want to have the bottleneck of having a
shitty page.
Mm.
But then so many people still don't
understand what a business expense means.
The coach is in there doing free rent for
the gyms.
Would you ever entertain doing 12 hours a
week
of coaching so you could have a free club
membership?
No. Well,
I actually nearly said yes to a role in
Qatar for coaching, but I think it tallied
out to be about the first 30 lessons I
gave were rent, and then
the next 30 or 40, whatever I gave
was profit.
And I was just like, "No."
And I did the maths for someone in Discord
the other day.
I said, "Bro,
if you pay your rent to the gym
and deduct it and have those
hours back," he was better off
financially.
Mm.
But he was just so worried about keeping
his costs down.
I think that's a lot of business owners,
right?
Obviously, a lot of golf coaches as well,
they all want to sell a 10-pack for
$1,000,
but they don't want to pay $9.95 to
take a watermark off CapCut.
Mm.
Right?
Yeah.
A lot of business owners are like that.
They want to sell that big ticket-
[laughs] It's true
...
but they don't want to buy the big ticket
that actually makes them more money
as well.
Yeah.
They spend an hour looking for a way to
edit without watermark.
Yep.
You're like, "Just pay the-
[laughs] Yeah
... $10, bro."
Exactly.
Okay. This one looks fairly straight down.
So I would aim at
that other flag as your line,
and then obviously
we're putting towards our flag. Oh,
could be a chance. Declan,
you got to get this.
This could be the greatest putt.
Oh.
Oh, how good.
If you had to give me harsh feedback,
not just on my golf swing, but on my
work, what would it be?
What could I do better?
I think you do everything well, which
is why I follow you,
which is why I'm here today.
But we're all in different areas
of our businesses, right? And some people
need the love.
Some people need the harsh love.
And I think it's just trying to find the
balance between those.
Obviously, you're known for no bullshit,
right, straight to the
point.
And I like what you say in the Discord,
right, where you're like, "Remember,
if I just said, 'Yeah, mate,
looks good,' you'd be an asshole, right?"
Yeah.
So giving them that tough love
is what they need.
But there are, I think,
some times with you,
and you would know this,
where you
have two coffees and a new tonic
and you're just like,
"I'm going to just rip
everyone to shreds," right?
Because I'm very much
like that myself, right?
Some days I get my day started and
couple of lessons start off
and they're not ideal,
or my fucking camera angles
aren't in the right spot,
and it's just like a flow on
and it affects everyone
else.
Yeah, okay.
So I think you can sometimes,
not just you, but myself as
well, trying to blur
that line between being way too harsh
and then
sympathetic.
Yeah.
But it's like 1% of what you do.
But without being what you
are, you wouldn't be where you are.
I call it chemotherapy.
You give them enough that you save them,
but you take them close.
I think for the time being,
I'm going to stick to
helping people with their-
[laughs]
... businesses.
Thank you very much. Been very helpful
and insightful today.
No, it's cool. Thanks for
coming out, and it was a pleasure.
Mate, I can't wait to see. This
is like a Uno Reverse +4
because we've managed to play golf
together, talk about business,
but also not only
will this benefit what I'm doing,
I'll hopefully be able to benefit what
you're
doing.
Yeah, 100%.
Fantastic. Synergy is what we call that.
Synergy.
Get a YouTube video out of it,
some content, and I hope
that I can give you a
little bit of an uptick with my shanks
and shots, whatever.
Well, hopefully we can fix all
that like we did on the-
I don't know if I'm going to be back here
for a while, Ryan
... well, again,
you've got to put in the work
if you want to improve. So, yeah.
So next week, Ryan comes to jujitsu.
[laughs]